I know that the effects of the current
corona virus pandemic have turned our
lives upside down but I wanted to take a
moment to assure you that your village
is here for you as we continue to
navigate these uncharted waters it's
important that you know you're not alone
in this
your village leadership including Police
Fire and Public Works have been meeting
and conferring with authorities
regarding the impacts of kovat 19 for
weeks so when I say that we are not
panicked were prepared I mean it since
March 11th our senior staff have been
meeting daily on this issue I have
joined these meetings and paid close
attention to the quickly moving
situation we are living in a new reality
one where we know that kovat 19 is a
very real threat and as the situation
unfolded we didn't sit back and wait
we've been listening to experts watching
the data and doing our part to help
flatten the curve we took measured steps
with forethought and clarity on March
12th we made the announcement that the
village hall and the other municipal
buildings would be closed to the public
but your village still came to work the
next day your police officers your
firefighters and paramedics your public
works crews community development
finance and administration personnel
continue to serve our businesses and
residents while some of our
administrative staff are now set to
telework we continue providing services
to our residents and businesses
seamlessly by phone email and online we
set up our dedicated website wwww
marketing
from the CDC about proper hand washing
technique and social distancing and we
have continued to communicate since
March 12 we have issued statements every
few days on this issue to let you know
what we're doing to keep you safe on
march 20th I issued a declaration of
emergency for Lombard
this declaration will help us access
federal funding will allow us to
maintain certain administrative
functions and when necessary take swift
action to address village needs also on
March 20th Governor Pritzker issued a
stay at home order for Illinoisans
that did not hold an essential job of
course this doesn't include the people
on the front lines because they're the
ones out there every day risking their
lives for ours there will never be
enough kind words or enough thank-yous
to the men and women in health care to
our first response or Ponder's and to
everyone else still serving their
communities my heart goes out to you and
I pray for your safety this
unprecedented change in daily life
resulted in an economic impact to the
village of Lombard specifically to small
businesses the heart and soul of our
community to do what we could to help I
also signed into effect several
executive orders one order suspended a
code provision that automatically
terminated liquor licenses for
businesses that are closed for more than
45 days another order permitted certain
restaurants to temporarily sell packaged
and sealed alcoholic beverages through
delivery and pickup
additionally in conjunction with other
utilities in Illinois the village
announced that it would not be
terminating water service or penalizing
customers who fall behind on water bill
payments we will do our best to work
with residents and businesses and to
come up with solutions I signed another
order to temporarily suspend the
issuance of solicitors tournaments any
resident or
this owner who encounters a solicitor
should immediately contact the Lombard
Police Department as we look into the
coming weeks we will continue to work
with our partners at the DuPage County
Health Department and the Illinois
Department of Health to determine the
next steps in our course of action and
we will have a lot of unknowns there is
one thing we can be sure of we will get
through this together we all need our
neighbors to stay inside to maintain
social distance and to continue to do
their parts as individuals that means
being kind to one another
and not taking more than you need at the
grocery store
it means checking in on our elderly
neighbor from a distance or over the
phone as we move forward I am urging
lombard residents to follow the
guidelines that have been established by
health care professionals and to follow
the restrictions put in place by the
stay at home order do not leave your
home for non-essential trips this is
important please stay at home if you are
elderly or have underlying health issues
please stay at home if you are sick or
feel like you're getting sick do not
risk your neighbors health or your own
stay at home you are risking your life
and the lives of your friends family and
neighbors if you choose to ignore these
restrictions while these sacrifices
carry with them frustrations from rest
for residents and headache for business
owners the only way out of this is to go
through it together
the more we adhere to these rules the
sooner we can flatten the curve and
eventually get back to rebuilding I know
the news can feel overwhelming I know it
I see it but I also see our amazing
stories coming from our community
volunteer bus drivers helping deliver
food to children in need people in the
community trying new restaurants just to
support local businesses positive
messages written with chalk on sidewalks
by children these are the things that
make us Lombard strong this is what
makes me so incredibly proud to be your
village president but also to be your
neighbor I cannot thank each and every
one of you enough for your support
during this time and what we need more
now more than ever is your cooperation
please please stay at home and away from
other people this is to help your
neighbors your medical professionals and
your first responders to our residents
we will continue to serve you when you
need us the most
to our businesses we will work with you
to support you through the unknown we
will and always remain lombard strong it
is my honor to serve as your village
president god bless you god bless
Lombard and god bless the United States
of America
you